Doug Raffle

http://stat.wvu.edu/~draffle/raffled@gmail.com | 724.518.7446

EDUCATION

WEST VIRGINIA UNIVERSITY

MS IN STATISTICS

Expected Aug 2015 | Morgantown, WV

CALIFORNIA UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE MINOR IN MATHEMATICS Grad. May 2013 | California, PA

LINKS

Portfolio://

stat.wvu.edu/d@affle/portfolio.html

Github://

github.com/raffled/

LinkedIn://

linkedin.com/in/raffled

SKILLS

MAJOR SKILL SETS

Data Technologies
Statistical Modeling
Multivariate Analysis
Data Mining/Machine Learning
Big Data Analytics
Software Development
Data Visualization
Text Mining
Technical Writing/Presentation

TECHNOLOGIES/PLATFORMS

Microsoft Office JMP Hadoop/MapReduce Linux/Unix RStudio

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Strong

R

HTML/XML

MT-X

Markdown/R Markdown

Familiar

C/C++

Java

JavaScript

LISP

Python SQL

SUMMARY

I am a data scientist and statistician with a strong background in both software development and statistical analysis. My experience in teaching and research has allowed me the opportunity to not only learn and implement a variety of statistical and machine learning models, but to hone my presentation skills and work closely with experts in a variety of fields. My goal is to find a challenging position where I can solve novel problems and make data-driven policy recommendations.

EXPERIENCE

WEST VIRGINIA UNIVERSITY | GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

August 2013 - May 2015 | Department of Statistics | Morgantown, WV

- Work with lecturers and professors to develop teaching and evaluation strategies.
- Teach and grade for laboratory and lecture sections of undergraduate Statistics courses, where the students review concepts and get hands-on experience using Statistics to solve realistic problems.
- Work in our Statistics Tutoring Center to help students master coursework from any of our department's classes, from 100- to 400-level, in a one-on-one environment.

WEST VIRGINIA UNIVERSITY | GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May 2014 - Sept. 2014 | West Virginia Dialect Project | Morgantown, WV

- Consulted with linguists and to evaluate and create analysis workflows.
- Cleaned, shaped, and performed Exploratory Data Analyis on large data files generated by speech-processing software (Praat).
- Built and evaluated Linear and Generalized Linear Mixed Effects models used in the investigation of sociolinguistic trends.
- Reported results in a manner accessible to wide audiences.

CALIFORNIA UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Sept. 2010 - May 2013 | The Lexomics Project | California, PA

- Used Hierarchical Clustering algorithms to analyze works of literature for stylistic variation.
- Presented at several conferences and co-authored a paper explaining our methodology and results.

THE WHEATON LEXOMICS GROUP | RESEARCH INTERN

Summer 2012 | Wheaton College | Norton, MA

- Worked directly with professors of Statistics and Computer Science to develop, test, and document software for performing and visualizing cluster analysis in text mining.
- Evaluated and implemented various machine learning and statistical methods to further analyze the features that are most indicative of clustering behavior and perform cluster validation.

AWARDS AND GRANTS

- 2014 Outstanding Graduate Teaching Assistant Award (WVU)
- 2012 Second Place Student Scholarship and Creativity Day (CalU)
- 2011 Jesse B. Guttman Student Research Grant
- 2011 Third Place Student Scholarship and Creativity Day (CalU)